<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>EPFL news</title><link>http://actu.epfl.ch/search/crcl/</link><description>News feed from crcl</description><atom:link href="http://actu.epfl.ch/feeds/rss/crcl/en/" rel="self"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2023 17:26:15 +0100</lastBuildDate><item><title>Lecture on Multi-Agent Robotic Construction at CIS</title><link>http://actu.epfl.ch/news/lecture-on-multi-agent-robotic-construction-at-cis</link><description>


&lt;img height="181" width="324" src="https://actu.epfl.ch/image/130879/324x182.jpg"&gt;

&lt;div class="publish_date"&gt;
  23.03.23 -  Prof. Parascho was invited to give a lecture on multi-agent robotic processes at CIS. The recording is now available to &lt;a class="notion-link-token notion-enable-hover" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=TDZfLca98gY" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;watch online&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Professor Stefana Parascho gave a lecture on December 5 about the cooperative relationships between humans, robots, and the built environment. Towards expanding the role of machines beyond siloed material-specific constructions, Prof. Parascho discusses new means of information exchange and interaction that would allow for robots to be employed in more design and existing construction contexts. The lecture was part of the CIS “Get to know your neighbors” Seminar Series and is now available to &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=TDZfLca98gY"&gt;watch online&lt;/a&gt;. More information about the event and series can be found on the &lt;a href="https://www.epfl.ch/research/domains/cis/center-for-intelligent-systems-cis/events/gtkyn/prof-stefana-parascho/"&gt;CIS website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;div class="authors"&gt;
  
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2023 17:26:15 +0100</pubDate><guid>http://actu.epfl.ch/news/lecture-on-multi-agent-robotic-construction-at-cis</guid></item><item><title>Construction Robotics Review Paper Available Online</title><link>http://actu.epfl.ch/news/construction-robotics-review-paper-available-onlin</link><description>


&lt;img height="181" width="324" src="https://actu.epfl.ch/image/130875/324x182.jpg"&gt;

&lt;div class="publish_date"&gt;
  23.03.23 -  Construction Robotics: From Automation to Collaboration by Prof. Dr. Stefana Parascho is available for &lt;a class="notion-link-token notion-enable-hover" href="https://www.annualreviews.org/doi/abs/10.1146/annurev-control-080122-090049" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;download online&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;As part of Volume 6 of the Annual Review of Control, Robotics, and Autonomous Systems, the review paper Construction Robotics: From Automation to Collaboration details the evolution of robotics in architecture and construction from its first applications over 40 years ago to its critical role in complex digital assemblies today. The review focuses on field-wide trends toward more collaborative and flexible processes that would allow robots to see more widespread use in conventionally challenging environments, such as construction sites. The paper was written by Prof. Dr. Stefana Parascho and is &lt;a href="https://www.annualreviews.org/doi/abs/10.1146/annurev-control-080122-090049"&gt;downloadable online now&lt;/a&gt; in advance of final publication in May 2023.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;div class="authors"&gt;
  
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2023 17:21:50 +0100</pubDate><guid>http://actu.epfl.ch/news/construction-robotics-review-paper-available-onlin</guid></item><item><title>Publication of ACADIA '21 'Realignments: Toward Critical Computation'</title><link>http://actu.epfl.ch/news/publication-of-acadia-21-realignments-toward-criti</link><description>


&lt;img height="181" width="324" src="https://actu.epfl.ch/image/127813/324x182.jpg"&gt;

&lt;div class="publish_date"&gt;
  11.01.23 -  The proceedings from ACADIA 2021 ‘Realignments: Toward Critical Computation’ have been published and are available for &lt;a href="https://2021.acadia.org/publication/ACADIA_2021_Proceedings_LowRes.pdf"&gt;free download&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/ACADIA-2021-Realignments-Computation-Architecture/dp/B0BJT2V3TD/ref=sr_1_1?crid=1EO7SUMOPZCDM&amp;amp;keywords=acadia+2021+realignments&amp;amp;qid=1667434720&amp;amp;qu=eyJxc2MiOiIwLjg1IiwicXNhIjoiMC4wMCIsInFzcCI6IjAuMDAifQ%3D%3D&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;sprefix=2021+acadi%2Cstripbooks%2C75&amp;amp;sr=1-1"&gt;purchase in print&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Following the conclusion of ACADIA 2021 ‘Realignments: Toward Critical Computation’ last year, the conference proceedings have been published as a single volume containing all of the technical papers, projects, field notes, keynote conversations, awards, and workshops from ACADIA’s 40th anniversary. The conference featured projects exploring critical computation design and fabrication across many scales and media, as well as keynote panels on topics ranging from emancipatory design to the ethics of designing with AI and data. Among the editors of the proceedings is Prof. Dr. Stefana Parascho, director of &lt;a href="https://www.epfl.ch/labs/crcl/"&gt;CRCL&lt;/a&gt;. The proceedings are now available as a &lt;a href="http://2021.acadia.org/publication/ACADIA_2021_Proceedings_LowRes.pdf"&gt;free PDF download&lt;/a&gt; or for purchase as a print edition through &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/ACADIA-2021-Realignments-Computation-Architecture/dp/B0BJT2V3TD/ref=sr_1_1?crid=1EO7SUMOPZCDM&amp;amp;keywords=acadia+2021+realignments&amp;amp;qid=1667434720&amp;amp;qu=eyJxc2MiOiIwLjg1IiwicXNhIjoiMC4wMCIsInFzcCI6IjAuMDAifQ%3D%3D&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;sprefix=2021+acadi%2Cstripbooks%2C75&amp;amp;sr=1-1"&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;div class="authors"&gt;
  
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2023 11:54:10 +0100</pubDate><guid>http://actu.epfl.ch/news/publication-of-acadia-21-realignments-toward-criti</guid></item><item><title>Edvard Bruun presents ZeroWaste at ACADIA 2022: Hybrids &amp; Haecceities</title><link>http://actu.epfl.ch/news/edvard-bruun-presents-zerowaste-at-acadia-2022-hyb</link><description>


&lt;img height="181" width="324" src="https://actu.epfl.ch/image/128240/324x182.jpg"&gt;

&lt;div class="publish_date"&gt;
  11.01.23 -  Congratulations to CRCL external advisee Edvard Bruun, who presented research on robotic dis- and reassembly of timber structures at ACADIA 2022.&lt;br /&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In collaboration with Erin Besler and the Princeton Form Finding Lab, PhD candidate and CRCL advisee Edvard Bruun presented ZeroWaste: Towards the Robotic Disassembly and Reuse of Conventional Timber Stick Frame Structures at ACADIA 2022. The project proposes a computational method of deconstructing and reassembling an existing frame structure as a means of reducing the use of new construction material. The process begins by utilizing 3D imaging technology to build a topological graph of the structural members, which represents how they are supported. This is used to generate a robotic disassembly sequence executed by multiple robotic arms for a scaffold-free dis- and reassembly. Though the paper demonstrates this process on a prototype structure, the approach is designed to be adaptable to similar structures towards rethinking material circulation and waste streams in construction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;div class="authors"&gt;
  
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2023 11:34:47 +0100</pubDate><guid>http://actu.epfl.ch/news/edvard-bruun-presents-zerowaste-at-acadia-2022-hyb</guid></item><item><title>Bamboo installation in the Architecture faculty building</title><link>http://actu.epfl.ch/news/bamboo-installation-in-the-architecture-faculty-bu</link><description>


&lt;img height="181" width="324" src="https://actu.epfl.ch/image/123937/324x182.jpg"&gt;

&lt;div class="publish_date"&gt;
  26.09.22 -  In collaboration with GCM, ITKE and an independent artist, the CRCL unveils a lightweight bamboo structure at the heart of the Architecture faculty building.&lt;br /&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://bamx.epfl.ch/"&gt;BamX&lt;/a&gt;, a geodesic dome made from deployable bamboo cylinders, is displayed from September 22nd to 27th in the &lt;a href="https://plan.epfl.ch/?room==SG%20094.11"&gt;SG hall&lt;/a&gt; of EPFL campus. The CRCL team collaborated with the &lt;a href="https://gcm.epfl.ch/"&gt;Geometric Computing Laboratory&lt;/a&gt; of EPFL, the &lt;a href="https://www.itke.uni-stuttgart.de/"&gt;ITKE Institute&lt;/a&gt; of Building Structures and Structural Design from the University of Stuttgart, and with Alison Martin, an independent artist, to erect this 10.4m in diameter and only 160kg computationally optimized bamboo structure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;div class="authors"&gt;
  
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2022 15:27:40 +0200</pubDate><guid>http://actu.epfl.ch/news/bamboo-installation-in-the-architecture-faculty-bu</guid></item><item><title>Reuse through creative computation at ENAC 20 years anniversary</title><link>http://actu.epfl.ch/news/reuse-through-creative-computation-at-enac-20-ye-3</link><description>


&lt;img height="181" width="324" src="https://actu.epfl.ch/image/123939/324x182.jpg"&gt;

&lt;div class="publish_date"&gt;
  26.09.22 -  CRCL presented a robotic assembly prototype of reused concrete for the ENAC 20 years anniversary exhibition&lt;br /&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The interdisciplinary ENAC faculty of EPFL, gathering architecture, civil engineering and environmental sciences, &lt;a href="https://www.epfl.ch/schools/enac/about/events/20-years-enac/"&gt;celebrated its 20 years&lt;/a&gt;. For its exhibition, CRCL showcased one of the ongoing PhD research of the lab, through a small scale robotic assembly of concrete rubbles. The research is caried by PhD candidate &lt;a href="https://people.epfl.ch/maxence.grangeot"&gt;Maxence Grangeot&lt;/a&gt;, under the supervision of Prof. Dr. Stefana Parascho from &lt;a href="https://crcl.epfl.ch/"&gt;CRCL&lt;/a&gt; and Prof. Dr. Corentin Fivet from &lt;a href="https://sxl.epfl.ch/"&gt;SXL (Structural Xploration Lab&lt;/a&gt;). His thesis benefits expertise from both laboratories, at the intersection of structural reuse of construction waste and collaborative robotic assembly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;div class="authors"&gt;
  
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2022 15:26:12 +0200</pubDate><guid>http://actu.epfl.ch/news/reuse-through-creative-computation-at-enac-20-ye-3</guid></item><item><title>Lecture at the Smart Living Lab</title><link>http://actu.epfl.ch/news/lecture-at-the-smart-living-lab</link><description>


&lt;img height="181" width="324" src="https://actu.epfl.ch/image/119996/324x182.jpg"&gt;

&lt;div class="publish_date"&gt;
  09.06.22 -  Stefana Parascho was invited to give a lecture at the Smart Living Lab. Watch the recording &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=aVBkiVCDc94"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Robotics and digital technologies have been changing the way we design and build. But the question today is no longer “&lt;em&gt;What can we do with a robot?”&lt;/em&gt; but “&lt;em&gt;What is the role of the machine in the design and construction process?” &lt;/em&gt;We can address this question by engaging with robots and algorithms from a different perspective: exploring the role of technology in the design process and finding new ways of information exchange between different agents of the process – humans and machines.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Robots working cooperatively, humans and robots building together, architects designing along with machines – the presented work explores the various relationships between designers and machines, between software and hardware, and opens up new questions and avenues for expanding the impact of digital technology onto our built environment. From scaffold-free assembly to robots employed for material reuse and computational tools designed to ease interdisciplinary knowledge exchange – the goal is to move beyond the development of material-specific processes and towards strategies for successfully integrating these new technologies into design. Ultimately, this requires the exploration of new roles for machines, new relationships between humans, algorithms and robots, and new connections across disciplines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;div class="authors"&gt;
  
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2022 18:54:49 +0200</pubDate><guid>http://actu.epfl.ch/news/lecture-at-the-smart-living-lab</guid></item><item><title>Welcome to CRCL!</title><link>http://actu.epfl.ch/news/welcome-to-crcl</link><description>


&lt;img height="181" width="324" src="https://actu.epfl.ch/image/119994/324x182.jpg"&gt;

&lt;div class="publish_date"&gt;
  09.06.22 -  The Lab for Creative Computation (CRCL) has started its activities in March 2022 under the direction of Stefana Parascho.&lt;br /&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Keep an eye on this &lt;a href="https://www.epfl.ch/labs/crcl/news/"&gt;page&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://actu.epfl.ch/subscription/news/subscribe/595"&gt;subscribe&lt;/a&gt; to receive an email for each news!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;div class="authors"&gt;
  
&lt;/div&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2022 18:39:14 +0200</pubDate><guid>http://actu.epfl.ch/news/welcome-to-crcl</guid></item></channel></rss>